이야기 2화 '서점'에 대해서 선현우 & 최경은
Iyagi Episode 2 'About Bookstores' Sun Hyun-woo & Choi Kyung-eun
안녕하세요. Talk To Me In Korean의 이야기 두번째 시간입니다.
Hello. This is the second episode of Talk To Me In Korean's Iyagi.
안녕하세요.
Hello.
선현우입니다.
I'm Sun Hyun-woo.
안녕하세요.
Hello.
최경은입니다.
I'm Choi Kyung-eun.
네, 여러분, 반갑습니다.
Yes, everyone, nice to meet you.
지금은 이야기 두번째 시간 이죠?
This is the second episode of Iyagi, right?
네, 맞아요.
Yes, that's right.
오늘은 서점에 대해서 이야기를 해 볼 거예요.
Today, we're going to talk about bookstores.
서점이요?
Bookstores?
네, 서점.
Yes, bookstores.
서점.
Bookstores.
네, 책을 파는 곳이죠?
Yes, it's the place where they sell books, right?
네, 맞아요.
Yes, that's right.
네.
Yes.
서점에서는 책을 파는데 사실 책이 아닌 다른 물건들도 많이 팔잖아요?
They sell books at bookstores, but actually, they also sell many other things that aren't books, right?
네, 맞아요.
Yes, that's right.
경은 씨 서점에 자주 가세요?
Kyung-eun, do you go to bookstores often?
아니요.
No.
자주 못 가요.
I can't go often.
자주 못가요?
You can't go often?
아니면 자주 안 가요?
Or do you not go often?
자주 못가요.
I can't go often.
가고 싶은데 못 가요.
I want to go, but I can't.
시간이 없어요.
I don't have time.
시간이 없어요?
You don't have time?
네.
Yes.
너무 바빠요.
I'm too busy.
그래요?
Really?
현우 씨는요?
How about you, Hyun-woo?
저는 서점에 자주 가요.
I go to bookstores often.
아, 얼마나 자주 가요?
Ah, how often do you go?
음 ...
Hmm...
일주일에 두 번?
Twice a week?
와, 진짜요?
Wow, really?
네.
Yes.
일주일에 두 번 가고,
I go twice a week,
그리고 그냥 실제 서점 말고 인터넷 서점도 자주 가는 것 같아요.
and I think I also visit online bookstores often, not just physical bookstores .
그런데 인터넷 서점에서는 책을 안 사요.
But I don't buy books from online bookstores.
왜요?
Why?
그냥 책은 음 ...
Just books are, well...
직접 손으로
I tend to buy them after touching them with my own hands
예.
근데 저도 서점에 가는 거 좋지만, 인터넷 서점이 훨씬 싸요.
Yes.
But even though I also like going to bookstores, online bookstores are much cheaper.
한국에서는요.
In Korea.
맞아요.
That's right.
그건 알고 있어요.
I know that.
알고 있는데 음 ...
I know that, but, hmm...
그냥 서점에서 직접 책을 보고 서점에서 책을 사요.
I just want to see the books myself at the bookstore , so I buy books at bookstores.
그런데 제가 젤 좋아하는 서점은 종각에 있는
By the way, my favorite bookstore is the one in Jonggak,
영풍문고인데, 아~ 영풍문고.
Youngpoong Bookstore, Ah~ Youngpoong Bookstore.
네, 아세요?
Yes, do you know it?
유명하죠.
It's famous.
네.
Yes.
영풍문고 정말 좋아요.
Youngpoong Bookstore is really good.
얼마 전에 큰 공사를 했어요.
but not long ago, they did major construction work.
아, 그래요?
Oh, really?
네,
Yes,
그래서 영풍문고가 지하 1층,
so Youngpoong Bookstore is on the first basement floor
지하 2층에 있는데 문구 (아,
and second basement floor, (ah,
정말요?)
really?)
그러니까 공책, 연필, 펜 또는 카메라, 스피커, 뭐, 컴퓨터 ...
I mean notebooks, pencils, pens, or cameras, speakers, well, computers...
서점 맞아요?
Is that a bookstore?
네.
Yes.
지하 1층만 서점이에요.
Only the first basement floor is the bookstore.
지하 2층에 그렇게 문구,
since there's stationery on the second basement floor,
전자 제품 이런 것들이 정말 많아서,
and electronic goods like that are really plentiful,
더 돈을 많이 벌고 있는 것 같아요.
I think they are making more money.
아, 그렇군요.
Ah, I see.
그렇지 않아요?
Don't you think so?
그런 것 같아요.
I think so.
네.
Yes.
사람들은 책도 보고 싶지만,
People want to see books too, but
서점에 갈 때는 그냥,
when they go to a bookstore, they just,
그냥 무언가를 보고 싶어서 가잖아요?
they go just because they want to look at something, right?
네, 그렇죠.
Yes, that's right.
그리고 돈을 쓰고 싶어서 가잖아요?
And they go because they want to spend money, right?
그래요?
Really?
음 ...
Hmm...
돈을 쓰고 싶어서 가는 거 아닌가요?
Don't they go because they want to spend money?
아니죠.
No, of course not.
그게 아니라 그냥 그냥 갔는데 그런 너무 예쁜 것들이 많아서 유혹에 빠져서 사는 거에요.
That's not it, they just went there and because there were so many pretty things, they fell into temptation and bought them.
돈을 쓰는 거죠.
So they end up spending money.
(아 ...
(Ah...
그럴 수도)
That could be)
저는 그래요.
At least I do.
저도 물론 돈을 쓰고 싶지는 않아요.
Of course, I don't want to spend money either.
물건을 가져올 수 있잖아요?
, right?
그래서 살 수 있잖아요.
So you can buy it.
그런 느낌 때문에 가고,
I go because of that feeling,
사실 보고 다 사지는 않아요.
but actually I don't buy everything I look at.
다 사면 큰일나죠.
If you buy everything, you'd be in big trouble.
맞아요.
That's right.
돈이 없겠죠?
You'd run out of money, right?
네, 큰일나요.
Yes, that would be trouble.
네, 그래서 서점에 가서 책도 보고, 문구도 보고,
Yes, so I go to bookstores and look at books, look at stationery,
컴퓨터도 보고,
look at computers,
새로 나온 카메라도 보고.
and look at newly released cameras.
그렇게 자주 해요.
I do that often.
아~ 저도 종로에 있는 반디앤루니스라는 서점을 좋아하는데
Ah~ I also like a bookstore called Bandi & Luni's in Jongno,
그 서점을 좋아하는 이유가 우리나라에서 처음으로 서점에 의자를 놨어요.
and the reason I like that bookstore is because they put chairs in a bookstore for the first time in our country.
맞아요.
That's right.
맞아요,
That's right,
네, 옛날에는 항상 사람들이 서서 책을 볼 수 밖에 없었거든요.
Yes, in the past, people always had no choice but to stand and read books.
그 점이 너무 좋아서,
so I liked that so much
그 뒤부터 반디앤루니스만 가요.
that since then, I only go to Bandi & Luni's.
네, 굉장히 편해요.
Yes, it's very convenient.
네, 맞아요.
Yes, that's right.
그런데 아셨어요?
But did you know?
그런 ...
Those...
다른 서점에도 의자가 이제 있어요.
Other bookstores also have chairs now.
네, 이제 생겼죠.
Yes, they have them now.
네, 네.
Yes, yes.
그래서 저도 영풍문고에 가서, 의자에 앉아서 책을 볼 때도 있고,
So I also go to Youngpoong Bookstore, and sometimes I sit in a chair to read books,
아니면 그냥,
or sometimes,
예 , 서서 볼 때도 있는데 저는 그 문구를 많이 볼 수 있어서 좋아요.
yeah, I just stand and read, but I like it because I can look at stationery a lot .
그래서 서점에 자주 가요.
So I go to bookstores often.
(아 ...
) 네.
(Ah...
) Yes.
저는 일부러 문구 있는 데는 잘 안가요.
I purposely avoid going to places with stationery.
돈을 쓰게 되니까.
Because I end up spending money.
네~ 그것도 이해가 됩니다.
Yes~ I understand that too.
네.
Yes.
여러분은 서점에 자주 가세요?
Everyone, do you go to bookstores often?
그리고 집 근처에 서점이, 큰 서점들이 많이 있나요?
And are there bookstores, many large bookstores, near your house?
네, 그리고 책을 많이
Yes, and do you read
읽으시나요?
books a lot?
당연하죠.
Of course.
아, 그런가요?
Oh, is that so?
네.
Yes.
아 ...
Ah...
네,
Yes,
TalkToMeInKorean.com의 이야기 두 번째 에피소드를 들어 주셔서 감사하고요,
thank you for listening to the second episode of TalkToMeInKorean.com's Iyagi,
여러분의 이야기를 들려 주세요.
and please tell us your stories.
네, 코멘트로 남겨 주세요.
Yes, please leave them in the comments.
네.
Yes.
그러면 저희는 코멘트 기다리고 있겠습니다.
Then we will be waiting for your comments.
안녕히 계세요.
Goodbye.
안녕히 계세요